Damilare O. Samuel

- 🔀 sdamilare420@gmail.com
- 08163502922
- Lagos, Nigeria
- in LinkedIn
- Github

PROFILE

Highly skilled Python software engineer, data scientist, and visionary leader with over four years of python crafting commercial experience applications for businesses. Seeking to join a global and well-structured organization to develop cutting-edge business solutions. Recognized for boosting operations and revenue by through targeted process improvements and resolving chronic application issues, enhancing the customer experience while minimizing downtime. Demonstrated 3 years of successful leadership, inspiring teams to excel in project delivery. Ready to contribute expertise to serve an impressive roster of clients and drive growth forward-thinking in organization.

EDUCATION

Applied Data Science

WorldQuant University ☑ 11/2023 – present

MSc in Computer Science

University of Lagos ☐ 2019 – 2021 | Yaba, Nigeria

BSc in Computer Science

Lagos State University ☑ 2011 – 2015 | Ojo, Nigeria

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Homefort Energy 2

Role: Senior Python Engineer

01/2023 - 12/2023 | Yaba, Nigeria

Project: A GaaS (gas as a service) product to serve retailers and SMEs across Lagos state.

- Design and implement robust APIs for different systems
- Implement the database architecture for the product
- Implement microservices to merge different product assets
- Deloy the app to cloud infrastructure
- Maintenance, fixed debugs, and optimized code base.

NEW WEPS 🗷

Role: CTO

08/2021 - 12/2022 | Abuja, Nigeria

Projects: A CBT app and a staff appraisal system app

- Hold strategic meetings with the management team and board to make informed decisions about the organization's affairs.
- Trained staff on software applications to meet organization goals, such as the CBT and the LMS app
- Redesigned organization website for security (HTTPS) purposes and improved the user experience
- Implemented technical training for the database administrator.
- Implemented CBT, boosting staff productivity by 50% through automated markings

Side Hustle 🛮

Role: Python Mentor

06/2022 - 12/2022 | Remote, Nigeria

Project: A food recipe app.

- Achieved significant improvement in trainees' track performance through effective mentorship and guidance.
- Spearheaded the creation and delivery of high-quality video content and text materials, benefiting over 1,000 students.
- Successfully trained on Python, Django, and Django REST concepts, complemented by interactive quizzes

Credit Renaissance Ltd

Role: Python Software Engineer 02/2021 – 07/2021 | Lagos, Nigeria

Project: A loan management app that manages almost 500 user records.

- Designed and implemented efficient database models, utilizing Django's ORM tools
- Led a team of three in developing the company's product
- Ensured robust web application security through authentication and authorization mechanisms and best practices

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages:

Python, SQL, and JavaScript

Frameworks and Web:

Django, Flask, Django REST, Fast API, SQL Workbench, Swagger API, Testing, Node, Express js, Paystack Payment Gateway, Docker, Redis, Bootstrap 4, CSS 3, HTML 5, Pandas, NumPy, SciKit Learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, and PyTorch

Version Control: Git and Github Databases:

MySQL DB, Postgres DB, Mongo DB and SQLite DB

Cloud Infrastructure:

Digital Ocean, Railway, Heroku, Python Anywhere, AWS, and VPS



Jobberman Soft Skills 🛭

- Apt listener.
- Strong communication.
- Great team player.
- Good time management skills.
- Creative thinking.
- Leadership skills.

 Revamped the loan management process, replacing the manual method with a new system, significantly boosting staff productivity by 100%

Tech Stack: Python, Django, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Postgres

Freelancer

Python Software Developer 04/2019 – 01/2021 | Remote

Projects: An e-commerce app, a food delivery app, machine learning apps, etc

Responsibility:

- Created beautiful and responsive websites and projects for diverse clients, ensuring a seamless user experience
- Expertly performed software testing to deliver bugfree and optimized web applications
- Leveraged the MySQL Workbench tool to design efficient database ER diagrams for streamlined data management

Bincom ICT Solutions

Role: Python Trainee

03/2019 - 04/2019 | Yaba, Nigeria

- Implemented Python scripts for data analysis with NumPy and Pandas
- Developed website using Django and fixed bugs

Moat Academy for Developers 🛮

Role: Software Developer Trainee 01/2019 – 03/2019 | Ikeja, Nigeria

Project: A web app that connects real estate agents to users

- Conducted software testing in Flask, uncovering bugs and troubleshooting issues
- Developed ER diagrams for databases using the MySQL Workbench tool



Teens in AI

AI Mentor

02/2023 - present | Remote, England

 Provide virtual mentorship for the teens in the International Women's Day (IWD) global hackathon challenge.

Empower Her Community \square

Python Facilitator

03/2022 - 04/2022 | Remote, Nigeria

• Co-facilitated the Flask training for the female techies.